

# PROFILE

Skilled full stack developer with 5+ years of experience, and 2+ years of experience with data analysis and artificial intelligence. Recognized for hard working ethic, love for learning and adaptability. Also proven on multiple occasions to raise money for events and help gather sponsorships.

# CONTACT

PHONE:

1 (925)-448-5457

WEBSITE: <a href="https://neelr.dev">https://neelr.dev</a>

GITHUB:

https://github.com/neelr

EMAIL: hi@neelr.dev

# **H**OBBIES

Learning new skills and technologies Organizing Hackathons Origami Listening to Music Boy Scouts Debate

#### **LANGUAGES**

Python: Keras, Pytorch, TensorFlow,

Flask, Numpy

Node.js: React/React Native, Next.js,

MongoDB, Express, Electron

Bash, C, C++, Java, SQL, HTML/CSS,

Theme-UI, Rust, Golang

# NEEL REDKAR

Aspiring Data Scientist and Web Developer

# **EDUCATION**

Diablo Valley College 2018 - Current

4.0 GPA - Intro to Computer Science; Programming with Java (Equivalent of AP COMPSCI); Algebra 2; Trigonometry; Chemistry

Dougherty Valley High School 2019 – 2023

# WORK EXPERIENCE/ CJECTONFERENCES

Summer of Making - Tech Lead/Organizer 2020-2021

Organized a program where people from all over the world could receive hardware grants to create projects in the summer of the pandemic. Helped people from 28 countries and 143 different cities learn and create projects. Raised over 50K in funding thanks to our GitHub sponsorship.

https://summer.hackclub.com

AngelHacks - Organizer Director of Technology 2019–2019

Successfully organized a hackathon in Los Angeles to help computer science education, raising over \$15,000 total with 130+ participants.

https://angelhacks.org

DVHacks II - Logistics Team 2019–2020

Organized the logistics of this hackathon and helped obtain sponsorships. Overall it was a great success with 220+ signups and many great sponsors! https://dvhacks.tech

Hack the Fog - Technology Team 2019–2020

The first high school hackathon to ever happen in San Francisco with 70+ attendees helping increase the amount of tech education inside of San Francisco. https://hackthefog.com

Hack the New Year - Director of Technology 2019–2020

Successfully organized a hackathon in Ohio to help building the website and designing workshops total of 30+ participants. <a href="https://hacknewyear.com">https://hacknewyear.com</a>

Google Next 19 2019–2019

Google offered me a free pass to Next19, which was an amazing experience! At Next19 I learned a ton about Google Cloud and their new technologies, including AutoML, one of the coolest things I saw. I also attended many workshops, learning about cloud innovations and DevOps that help me with cloud processing!

#### Projects/Awards

#### **Smart Recycle**

This is an app that uses machine learning and image recognition to help people sort their recycling between trash, recycling, and compost. This project is on the App Store and won 1<sup>st</sup> place in the community and 2<sup>nd</sup> place in the California Science Fair. https://github.com/neelr/SmartRecycle

# **Earthquake Prediction Using AI**

This is a science fair project where I used a neural network to try to predict whether an earthquake would happen, using seismic data 24 hours before the earthquake. This was very informative as I got to use libraries such as Keras and Numpy. I also learned how much energy goes into gathering data, as there was no prebuilt dataset for this project. <a href="https://github.com/neelr/EarthquakePrediction">https://github.com/neelr/EarthquakePrediction</a>. This project won 1<sup>st</sup> place in the CCC Science and Engineering Fair!

#### Flappy Bird Al

Built a neural network from scratch in javascript, learning intricacies and different architectures on the way. I utilized no prior libraries or tools, using only the primitive typings of javascript. It utilizes reinforcement learning to train an agent to play flappy bird as to not hit any of the poles. I learned a lot about how neural networks work, and different architectures. https://flappyai.hacker22.repl.co

# Ghym

Ghym was a hackathon project made at HackMerced, a college hackathon. Ghym is a P2P Cloup Computing network, where nodes on the network are able to send jobs to one another, unlike normal cluster's today. This allows for people to put their old computers to use, so that students and ai learners, can have a network where they can train their neural networks fast and efficiently! This ended up winning 1st place in the Moonshot category, also winning the best usage of MongoDB. https://github.com/neelr/ghym

#### **HabitBot**

Habitbot is an app that uses natural language processing, to create a chat application where students can chat to a bot which tries to help them stop their addiction. It can tell whether or not the test given indicates if they are improving, and accurately gives them advice on how to stop. This was an application of AI to help our schools, because many high schoolers end up getting addicted to drugs throughout their learning career. We won 3<sup>rd</sup> in the Congressional App Challenge in our district. https://github.com/neelr/HabitBot

# **Global COVID19 Registry**

This is the COVID19 Registry where people who have already gotten COVID19 register, and can be called on by hospitals, and the public, for help! This is because people recovered from COVID19 are safe and cannot transmit or get the virus. This allows for you to stay anonymous, and receive donor, or public help requests through email, and if you receive one you feel would be a good fit, respond and work with the person to get it done! It uses MongoDB with HIPAA level encryption, a Node.js backend, with Next.js, React, and Theme-UI all put together for the website! <a href="https://globalcovidregistry.org">https://globalcovidregistry.org</a>

# **Hack University**

This is another site that's gaining popularity with 65+ users! Hack University is a way for students to teach other people cool and interesting things, or for teachers to open source syllabuses! Anyone can easily and seamlessly create a new class and teach it, and it's even easier to enroll! This way, we can work together as a community to increase learning and education during the time of crisis which is COVID19! I'm currently working with teachers across the district to open source the syllabuses and zoom classes! https://university.hackclub.com

# **Templater**

A cli to create and share code templates and structure! This makes life super easy, so you don't have to create the React folder structure, and can create production ready structure in seconds! Also the best part about this, is since it has integration with GitHub, you can upload and download other people's structures, so the possibilities are endless! It also has a UI so you can browse other peoples templates. This helped me understand using Golang as a CLI, and on the server integrating it with firebase and GitHub authentication. Check it out at <a href="https://tmpltr.now.sh">https://tmpltr.now.sh</a> or the source at <a href="https://github.com/neelr/templater">https://github.com/neelr/templater</a>